Previously on Gilmore Girls.;
- She's not here yet.
- All right.
You'll have to entertain me
until she arrives.
- Okay, burger boy, dance.
- Will you marry me?
- What?
- Looking for something to shut you up.
I actually thought
you'd like to go with me.
- You did not.
- I did, too.
- You did not, because you are not stupid.
- Why, thank you.
Slimy and weaselly, yes. But stupid, no.
He was totally nice to you
and you were a big jerk.
If you like Tristan so much,
you go out with him.
- What did you do?
- You wanted something festive.
- You made me a Santa burger.
- It's no big deal.
No one ever made me something
quite this disgusting before.
So you're the big, strong protector?
Little princess needs a protector.
- What's your problem, man?
- Nothing.
- Don't like your girlfriend.
- Doesn't look that way.
- Were you on a date?
- What?
- You have an escort.
- No, it's Luke.
Which is her way of saying
we weren't on a date.
I didn't mean it like that.
- You don't want to fight me, Tristan!
- Why not?
'Cause l'll kill you, idiot!
What exactly is going on
between the two of you?
We're friends, that's it.
You're idiots, the both of you.
He has a thing for you.
No, he doesn't.
It's just a game to him or something.
He has a thing for you.
He does nothing but insult me
and make me miserable.
He has a thing for you.
Absolutely nothing.
- Come on.
- I'm sorry. I'm looking.
- But there is nothing in here.
- You're kidding, right?
No, everything in here I wear.
- What?
- I do. There's nothing to give up.
The red-and-black halter top.
- No.
- Why?
It's a classic.
It's got rhinestones
and zebra stripes on it.
- So?
- Tassels.
- Yes.
- It has tassels, Mom.
Okay. I've had this since I was 17.
I'm sorry. Did I mention the tassels?
You're heartless and unsentimental.
You are a hopeless pack rat.
I don't understand why I have to uproot
my happy family of clothing, anyway.
Because it's a charity rummage sale.
- I know.
- That you helped organize.
- Okay.
- And volunteered to run.
It was very hot in that room that day.
I was dehydrated.
They could have talked me into anything.
- It was your idea.
- Okay.
I'm a very sick woman,
and that should be apparent to anyone.
Get out of the way.
- What are you doing?
- Step away from the closet, please.
This is so unfair.
No, not that whole chunk.
Okay, take that. That's ugly.
Just that one. No.
Now, all of this goes.
Come to this dresser, open the drawer,
and take out...
everything you'd be embarrassed
to be wearing in a car accident.
Meet me downstairs.
Move!
OpenSubtitles recommends using Nord VPN
- Sweater.
- Over here.
- Jeans.
- In back of you.
A big, furry, purple thing
that could either be a hat...
a toilet paper cover,
or some kind of dirty hand puppet.
Mystery box on the left.
- Hey, Luke.
- Where do you want these?
- What do you have?
- Clothes, rags, some old pots and pans.
Kitchenware can go in the kitchen,
and the clothes right over there.
- Here, Grinch.
- Thank you.
- Who wants cheese?
- Are there crackers?
Somewhere in the state
of Connecticut, yes.
And in the Gilmore house?
- Who wants cheese?
- Me, please.
Kittens in the toilet poster?
- Another one?
- This one's signed.
There's a man in my kitchen!
Somebody call the constable.
- Your mom's a fruitcake.
- Fruitcakes by the door, please.
Goodbye, Rory.
I wish you luck with everything.
I appreciate that.
Okay, so rummage sale's Sunday.
Today's Tuesday.
At this rate we're going to be sleeping
in the yard by Thursday.
We've got to get this stuff
out of the living room.
- Hello.
- Go away.
I have a full set of dishes.
- Come on in, Taylor.
- Dishes in the kitchen, please.
Okay, but I have
to explain something first.
- Fine, go ahead.
- The butter dish has a small chip in it.
- Safety tip. Got it.
- It's fine.
I filed down the chip. If you place it
strategically on the table, nobody'll know.
Taylor, would you like to write
an instruction manual for the dishes?
- Could I?
- Notepad's in the kitchen.
That's nice.
- Put that back.
- But it has rhinestones on it.
The point of this is to get crap out,
not trade it in for new crap.
- Are you seeing this?
- Yes, I am.
I don't think you are,
because if you were...
you would see that this obviously
has 'Lorelai' written all over it.
- Fine. We'll get rid of it at next year's sale.
- Thank you.
- You guys are gonna love me.
- We already love you.
- No, I mean you're gonna really love me.
- We do.
Trust me, you guys are gonna so love me.
The love is starting to fade now.
I have here in my hand,
as requested by Ms. Lorelai Gilmore...
four fabulous tickets to The Bangles
at the Pastorella theater on Saturday.
- What?
- No!
- You love me?
- Baby, do I.
- These look like good seats.
- Ninth row, aisle.
I can't believe you got me my tickets.
How did you score these?
- Remember the Birnbaum wedding?
- Fiji Fantasy?
Yes. They were so thrilled
with the volcano cake...
they wanted to do something nice for me.
Since Mr. Birnbaum runs a ticket agency,
and I knew you were dying to go...
- so I asked him if he could...
- Make four girls very happy.
- Yeah, and he did.
- Huzzah for the Birnbaums!
Sookie, if you got four tickets,
and you and mom go...
then that means...
One for you and one for Lane.
Chickadee!
This is gonna be a very special night.
You know what a special night deserves?
What?
- A new outfit.
- Mom.
- Yes.
- No.
What could the problem be?
As I mentioned yesterday,
we will be holding a debate next week.
Your subject:
Did Charles I receive a fair trial?
The pros will represent the Parliament...
who deemed they had sovereignty.
The cons will represent the monarch...
and try and prove
that the charge against him was not legal.
What is fascinating, Mr. Dugray?
Nothing, Ms. Caldecott.
Nothing, Mr. Dugray?
My notes are fascinating, Ms. Caldecott.
Yes, they are fascinating, Mr. Dugray.
As I was saying...
the pro and con teams will each
have two minutes and thirty seconds...
for introductions, six minutes to debate...
three minutes for conclusions...
and five minutes for questions
from the audience.
The winner shall be decided
by a hand count from the rest of the class.
Does that sound like fun, Mr. Dugray?
- What?
- The debate. Does it sound like fun?
- Yes, it does.
- It does, doesn't it, Mr. Dugray?
It absolutely does, Ms. Caldecott.
More fun than staring
at Ms. Gilmore's ear?
- Yes, Ms. Caldecott.
- I think so, too.
Okay. Any questions?
Good. I'll assign your teams.
You, you, you, and you, con.
You, you, you, and you, pro.
- Who did she point to?
- Well, I think she...
You, you, you...
- Excuse me, Ms. Caldecott.
- Ms. Geller?
I wasn't sure who you pointed to just now.
Let's see. You, Ms. Lynn,
Ms. Grant, and Ms. Gilmore.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I am, but thank you for asking.
Okay, you...
you, you, and you, pro.
You and you, con.
- So I guess we should make a plan.
- To do what?
To work out our debate, Madeline.
- Yeah, right.
- We need a place to work.
- My house is out.
- Why?
- Because it is.
- We need a reason.
My mother is having
the entire place redone.
She wants all evidence of my father
out of there.
So unless you want to sit on no furniture...
and watch Harvey Fierstein
impersonators rip up the carpet...
paint everything white
and call it 'Angel's Kiss'...
then we're going to have to find
somebody else's house.
- My brother has the measles.
- My mom's having an affair.
I guess we could go to my house.
We're having a town rummage sale,
so it's kind of a mess...
but it's there.
Isn't your house kind of far?
- It's 30 minutes away by bus.
- Bus? I don't do bus.
- Lf you have a better suggestion...
- l'll drive.
- Okay. So then, tomorrow.
- Tomorrow.
Fine.
- Hey, Paris.
- Tristan, hi.
I was really hoping
we'd be in the same group.
- You were?
- Yeah.
We'd make the long hours of studying
go by a lot faster.
Plus, you and me on the same team.
We'd wipe the floor with the others.
I guess we'll just have to pair up
on something else then, huh?
- That would be good.
- Yeah, it would.
I'll see you later.
Bye, Madeline. Bye, Louise.
Tristan suddenly has very big eyes
for you, Grandma.
- Lucky.
- Stop it. He's just being nice.
- He should be so nice to me.
- And me.
We need to get to class.
- Tomorrow.
- Wow.
- Yep.
- All three of them?
'Double, double, toil and trouble.'
It should make
for an interesting afternoon.
'With the pricking of my thumbs,
something wicked this way comes.'
- You're doing well in Shakespeare class?
- Not bad.
- Good.
- Thanks.
So what's the plan?
We'll ask if I can go to a play
tomorrow night with you and Lorelai.
- A play?
- I think that's the safest word.
'Show' or 'concert' would be very bad.
- What about saying it's a movie?
- Too far from the truth, almost a lie.
But a play's not a lie?
It's far enough from the truth
that it might work...
but close enough to the truth...
that I think I could negotiate
a purgatory stint, if forced to.
- Play it is.
- Okay. We're going in.
- Are you sure it's an original Queen Anne?
- Yes, original.
- The joints look wrong.
- Joints are fine.
- They look new.
- Nothing's new. Whole store is old.
Do you have a certificate or a letter
saying that it's old?
- Yes, l'll write a letter.
- Okay.
I guess if it's really old, l'll take it.
We appreciate your business.
She just made a sale. Now's a good time.
Hi, Mama.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
- You look flushed.
- I do?
You ate candy, doughnut,
or Hostess fruit pie?
No, nothing. I'm fine.
- Hello, Mrs. Kim.
- Rory.
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
- I'm busy.
I know. Could I could go somewhere
tomorrow with Rory and her mom?
- Tomorrow's church.
- This would be after that.
After church we think about
what we heard in church.
I could think about what I heard in church
on the way to the show.
- Show?
- Play.
Not show, play. It's a play, Mama.
Tell me about this play. What's it about?
It's about a group of people
who own instruments...
and stand in front of other people,
holding them.
- What?
- I'm not sure what it's about.
- We could find out.
- You find out, then we talk.
Excuse me. I'd really like that letter,
if you don't mind.
Yes, l'm coming.
How's that purgatory negotiation looking?
Not good.
- What do we do now?
- I'll ask again later.
- Call me if you need anything.
- Thanks. I will.
If you want coffee, you'll have to wait.
Someone put a sign for the rummage sale
on your window.
You can have decaf now
if you're in a hurry.
You should call the cops about this.
We know how you feel
about public displays of town affection.
Your mom asked me to put it there, okay?
- And you said yes?
- She's not real good with no.
No, she's not.
Every second you laugh at me
is one second longer you wait for coffee.
Sorry. No laughing.
Margaret Atworthy dropped off
three boxes of City Council potholders...
and begged me to take her grandson.
People are getting crazy, man.
- What?
- What are you wearing?
We've already argued
about the sweatshirt.
Yes, but we have not argued
about the hat.
- What hat?
- The one on your head, Annie Oakley.
Great, isn't it?
It's nice you're trying
to single-handedly rebuild a bridge...
but stop buying other people's junk.
Money goes to charity.
I look cute. Case closed.
Finally, the coffee cavalry arrives.
- What do you think you're wearing?
- A hat.
- Take that off.
- What?
- That is not yours. Take it off.
- But l'll have hat hair.
- I'm talking about the sweatshirt.
- Calm down.
That is not yours.
No, I found it in the bags of stuff
for the sale.
So you just find something
and take it? Is that it?
- No, I paid for it.
- So that makes it all right?
It makes it legal.
What is the matter with you?
- Nothing's the matter.
- Luke.
Pour your own coffee.
Okay. Just a question.
Did anyone in town keep anything?
- Doesn't look like it.
- I'll never be civic-minded again.
You're doing a good thing.
- Sookie?
- I'm okay.
- Wave an arm.
- Here.
I got you.
Hold on. Something down here likes me.
I'm good. Hold on. Up, please.
Jeez, this stuff is like Tribbles.
Thank God, just in time.
Grab a bag
and move it to this side of the room.
Be very careful.
This pile tried to eat Sookie.
Maybe I should sic it on Paris
when she gets here.
God, that's right.
You're studying here today.
- Any minute, actually.
- This place is such a pit.
Don't worry about it.
They'll come in, make a face,
say something snotty...
we'll study, they'll leave.
I'm looking forward
to this whole day being over.
- Then I can concentrate on the concert.
- Yeah.
Lorelai, sweetheart,
would you come outside, please?
I want to know
where you want me to put these.
Coming, Patty.
Two very large porcelain squirrels.
- Set them free.
- Will do.
Wow! These are great.
They'll really come in handy
when we organize...
that giant marching band
we've been talking about.
I danced on these drums
at the Copacabana...
in 1969.
- Wow.
- It was a great act.
- I wore bananas.
- Please tell me you have a picture of that.
A lot of memories happened
on these drums.
But I guess it's time to move on.
Yeah, sure.
Now you'll have room
for that enormous tuba...
you've had your eyes on.
Leave these here.
Yeah, you, too. Bye.
- That was Lane.
- What's the verdict?
She decided to be stupid
and tell her mother the truth...
that she wanted to go to a rock concert
with us tonight in New York.
Stupid.
- I'm so sorry.
- I'm making coffee.
This looks really familiar.
That's mine. I saw it first...
and then I bought it, so it's mine now.
Really? Who brought it in?
I think Luke did,
and judging by his very hostile reaction...
he wasn't done wearing it yet.
- Oh, my. I wonder if...
- What?
I bet this was Rachel's.
Oh, my God, Rachel's?
Rachel? Who's Rachel?
Rachel was Luke's very serious girlfriend.
- It does look like her.
- When did Luke have a girlfriend?
This must have been,
what, five, six years ago?
Did she break that man's heart.
It was terrible.
How did I not know about this?
Honey, you had an 11-year-old kid,
and you were just moving into this house.
Plus Rachel traveled a lot.
She was a photographer.
- Archaeologist.
- Really?
Or flight attendant.
I can't believe I never even heard about it.
At least, I think so.
Luke never talks about it.
No one else likes to talk about it...
'cause he could kill you with that coffeepot
if he wanted to.
I never pictured Luke having a girlfriend
or a broken heart.
I would keep this hidden if I were you.
I've got to be going.
Trampoline class at 2:00.
- Bye, Patty.
- Bye-bye.
Thanks for the drums.
These all need to be mended.
- My room.
- Okay.
Rory, I think your friends are here.
She must be one great baby-sitter,
to earn enough money for that car.
Let's just get this over with.
Take heart, my dear.
Suffer today, party tonight.
- Hi.
Come on in.
- So did you guys find it okay?
- There's no sign on this street.
That's why I told you to turn right
at the big rooster statue.
- I thought you were kidding.
- No, we never kid about Monty.
- Monty?
- Monty, the rooster.
Monty the Magnificent.
- Everybody, this is my mom.
- Lorelai.
This is Louise, Madeline, and Paris.
Very good girl-group names.
Sorry about the house of horrors here.
Some crazy lady volunteered
to lead this charity thing.
We're trying to get her some help.
So make yourselves comfortable.
- Just yell when you guys want pizza.
- Okay.
So, do you guys want to work in here
or in the kitchen?
Whatever.
Okay.
Okay. So here's how it should go:
Madeline will do the introductions,
l'll handle the debate...
Rory will do the conclusion,
and Louise will take questions.
Why do you automatically
get to handle the debate?
Because l'm the most experienced at it.
Trust me, you want her to handle it.
She never gives up.
Le pit bull.
- So what is all this stuff?
- It's for a big town rummage sale.
- Like a charity thing?
- Yeah.
There's an old bridge falling apart,
and the town's trying to save it.
- Cool hat.
- Put that down. It's used.
- Vintage, dear.
- Filthy, darling.
There's a store near my therapist's office
who has the best vintage clothes.
I found an original Pucci top
for practically nothing.
Pucci is very big right now.
- Is this a Pucci?
- No, that's a Patty.
- A Patty?
- Miss Patty.
She's a dance teacher here.
These are some of her old costumes.
Here, Paris. Tristan might like this.
Can we just work, please?
I would love to have a boyfriend
that looked like Tristan.
Your boyfriend's no slouch either.
- No, he's not.
- Yes, 6'2' and feisty.
So how's it going?
Are you two still Joanie Loves Chachi?
- God, I hope not.
- You are still together, aren't you?
- We're still together.
- How long has it been?
- I don't know.
- You do, too.
- About a month.
- Lifers.
- Jeez.
- We have a debate to organize here...
and this conversation is veering towards
the subject of French kissing...
and glitter eye shadow: Trashy or trendy?
I have no intention of being humiliated
in front of the whole class...
because we had to study
in the middle of a carnival...
and you two couldn't
keep your eye on the prize.
I want to win and I am going to win.
So, how good of a kisser
is Paul Bunyan anyway?
Okay. Does anybody in town
have a peg leg?
- No.
- Hem these.
- So, tell me more about this Rachel.
- Why are you so curious?
Because everybody in town
knows everything about it...
- and I don't like to be out of the loop.
- It's old news.
Yes, but l'm fascinated. I mean...
I go to Luke's once a day.
Sometimes twice.
Three times if Michel's talked to a relative
and his accent's gotten thicker.
I feel I should know the whole story.
What happened? Where'd she go?
Rachel liked to move around a lot.
She was a very adventurous person.
She loved to climb things,
and fling herself off cliffs...
and dive into these really tiny lakes...
and ride big wild horses, and fly planes.
- So she was Wonder Woman.
- She was to Luke.
- I thought they were gonna get married.
- What happened?
The rumor is that Stars Hollow
was too small for her.
She wanted to live
somewhere more exciting.
But Luke didn't.
You know Luke. Lived here all his life.
He wouldn't even go away to college.
I think we're gonna have to bury him
in that diner.
- It's sad.
- Yeah.
Okay. I am done here.
I'm gonna stop by the Inn for a while.
Then l'm gonna go home
and change for the show tonight.
- We leave at 6:00.
- I will be here. Bye.
We'll need the actual quotes,
so learn them by heart.
What about using notecards?
Notecards look sloppy.
We will know our information.
- But the other teams will use notecards.
- And they'll lose.
- Bye, girls. Rory, see you tonight!
- Bye, Sookie.
What's tonight?
We have tickets to see The Bangles
at the Pastorella theater.
- In New York?
- Yeah.
Sounds potentially not boring.
It's gonna be great. The seats are amazing.
- Who are you going with?
- My mom and Sookie.
- You're kidding.
- What?
- You're going to a concert with your mom?
- Yeah.
I cannot imagine doing anything like that
with my mom.
We do stuff like this all the time.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- How old is your mom, anyway?
- Thirty-two.
Young.
That means she had you when she was...
She had her when she was 16.
We've done the math.
Can we 'ooh' and 'ah' about this quickly
and get to work?
- Sixteen. I'm sixteen.
- So am I.
We're all 16, okay.
Everybody in this room is 16.
- Paris is right. We should work.
- Thank you.
- I can't imagine having a baby at 16.
- Then keep your knees shut.
Very nice.
Do you think your mom is sorry
she got pregnant so young?
- Of course she is.
- Why, thank you.
- I didn't mean that. I just meant...
- I don't think she'd recommend it...
but I think she's happy
with how things turned out.
- I am?
- Yes, you are.
Okay. Just checking.
I'm starving. Is it pizza time yet?
- Are you guys hungry?
- I am.
- I can't eat dairy.
- Okay.
One with cheese, one without. Cokes?
- Yes, please.
- Me, too.
We're never going to finish.
I find your mother completely fascinating.
Funny. So does she.
- It's almost like having a big sister.
- And you like her, don't you?
- She's my best friend.
- Truly, completely fascinating.
- Rory, come in here a sec.
- I'll be right back.
How's it going in there?
- Truly, completely fascinating.
- Really?
We've basically gotten
no work done at all.
Paris is having a meltdown,
which is always fun.
Sounds it.
And, I don't know, we've just been talking.
I think you're actually making
some friends here.
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
They've just moved off the plan
to dump the pig's blood on me at prom.
Talking, chatting, no work being done.
There's friend potential going on.
Maybe. With Louise and Madeline,
at least.
Two out of three
formerly psychotic enemies. Not bad.
There. Pop-Tart appetizers to tide you over
until the pizza comes.
Thanks.
Hey, I have kind of a crazy idea.
That's never comforting, coming from you.
- Consider this, okay?
- Okay.
- We have four tickets to the show tonight.
- Yes, we do.
- What if I give them to you?
- What are you talking about?
Seems like you guys have a bonding thing
going on in there. It might be fun.
- What about you?
- You and I have bonded already.
If we bond any further,
we'll be permanently fused together.
You've talked about the concert
since you heard about it.
- I can still go.
- How?
Sookie and I can buy cheap seats there.
These tickets are ninth row, aisle.
Dream seats.
You don't have to do this.
But you have three years
of Chilton ahead...
and it'll be nice to have friendly people
to talk to there.
You seem to be getting along.
It might be good.
I totally don't mind. I just wanna see
the show. I don't care from what seat.
- Are you sure?
- Completely sure.
- Because l...
- Ladies!
- What are you guys doing tonight?
- Why?
We have these really great tickets
to see The Bangles...
and Rory thought you might like to come.
- Are you serious?
- No way.
Yeah, I mean, if you guys want to.
- I would love to go.
- Count me in.
- Paris, what about you?
- I can't.
- Yes, you can.
- No, I can't.
- Because you're busy doing what?
- I have homework.
She'll be there.
- Good.
- Great.
- He made it.
- Oh, he's handy. How great.
You wear it all the time?
- Just when she's breathing.
- It's a love thing.
- Thanks for the contribution.
- Okay, here.
With these tickets,
you're about to enter sacred space.
You will be treading on hallowed ground.
You will be walking like an Egyptian.
- Mom.
- Take them.
You're gonna have a great time.
The Bangles are the best!
They were my favorite group in
high school. I almost named you Susanna.
The day I found out
you had no musical talent at all...
- was the saddest day of my life.
- Sorry.
You say that now. Here. Okay.
These are probably located...
Hi.
Can you tell me where these seats are?
- Those are right in here.
- Oh, good. Girls.
Here's the deal.
Take your tickets, go to your seats.
Have the night of a lifetime. Bangle it up.
The second the concert is over,
meet us in front of the theater. Got it?
- Yes.
- Good. Now go!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Okay. Let's go make our noses bleed.
- After you.
- Which aisle is it?
- We're almost there.
I have never sat this close
to a stage before.
I've never really been to a concert before.
So I could be sitting in the back
and say the same thing.
- In here.
- Good.
Wow. These are amazing seats.
Yes, they are.
- What are they looking at?
- One guess.
Check it out, we've got fans.
- Was I right?
- You were right.
And before it's dark, they'll have every
picnic basket that's in Jellystone Park.
- Did you ever see Everest?
- No.
It's a good movie.
We must be getting close.
We're running out of rows.
And 1,000.
- Okay. We're here.
- Great.
Okay. This is fine.
Yep. Not bad at all.
What?
What is so funny?
These are the worst seats
in the entire world.
- They are, aren't they?
- Oh, my God! It's so funny.
- Don't you think this is funny?
- You know, I don't.
I'm sorry.
They're starting! Do you have a lighter?
You mean a flamethrower. Get it?
A flamethrower, 'cause it's so far.
Ladies and gentlemen, The Bangles!
- Was Rachel pretty?
- What?
- I'm just curious. Was she pretty?
- She was pretty.
- What kind of pretty?
- What do you mean?
Was she a Catherine Zeta-Jones
kind of pretty...
or a Michelle Pfeiffery pretty, or...
She was an Elle MacPherson
kind of pretty.
- Really?
- Yep.
- That's an intense kind of pretty.
- You're not kidding.
I never pictured Luke
with an Elle MacPherson kind of pretty.
No? Pictured him more
with a Lorelai Gilmore kind of pretty?
The air up here must be very thin,
because you're delirious.
- And you're jealous.
- What?
- You're jealous of Rachel.
- You're accusing me of being jealous...
of a woman who dumped a man
l'm not even interested in five years ago?
- Yes.
- You don't think that's crazy?
- I do think that's crazy.
- Right, l'm not jealous.
Yeah, you are.
Oh, my God! He is so gorgeous.
I guess.
There's a massive party going on
right around the corner.
- So?
- So they invited us.
- Who?
- Jess and Sean.
We've been talking to them.
They're extremely cool.
- Are we going?
- Going where?
To the party.
- There's a concert going on.
- The band won't miss us.
- We can't just leave, Louise.
- It's America, Rory.
- We have to meet my mom after the show.
- Oh, come on.
What do you mean, 'Oh, come on'?
We have to meet my mother
after the concert.
The band may not miss us,
but Lorelai sure will.
These guys are so cute.
- Great, but we're not going anywhere.
- What, are you afraid?
Of going out into a strange city
with guys I don't know? Yeah.
- Please?
- No!
- Well, we're going.
- No, you're not.
- Paris? Join, please?
- No, thanks.
Fine. Come on, Madeline.
And just what am I supposed
to tell my mother?
That you're a very good little girl.
The party's in a building on the corner
of Waverly and First. Try to get away.
We'll be back
by the time the concert's over.
You know, I really like this band.
- Well?
- I couldn't find Mom or Sookie anywhere.
So what do we do now?
I guess we just wait here
for them to find us.
Okay.
I can't believe Louise and Madeline
would just leave like that.
- They've done it before.
- Nice.
Yeah, well.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Maybe.
- What could you possibly see in Tristan?
- You wouldn't understand.
- Is it just that he's cute?
- Partly.
'Cause there are a lot of cute guys
in the world.
Not like Tristan.
- He's just such a jerk.
- He's not always a jerk.
- No?
- No.
Okay.
When is he not a jerk?
I've known Tristan a really long time.
We've been in the same class
since kindergarten.
- Really?
- Yes.
And, well,
he has things in his life that are hard.
His parents, not so great.
- We have that in common.
- Okay.
- He kissed me once.
- He did?
- Sixth grade. On a dare.
- How romantic.
You just don't know him like I do.
Okay, I believe you.
I just think maybe you could do better.
I know he's flirting with me to get to you...
but at least he's flirting with me.
- Hey.
- There you are.
Think fast. T-shirts for all the girls...
because l'm the Good Witch...
Aren't you missing a couple of kids?
- They left.
- Excuse me?
- Madeline and Louise met these guys...
- What guys?
They were sitting behind us,
and they were having a party.
- Unbelievable!
- What's going on?
- They left.
- What?
Let's go. Come on. Move!
If I leave the house with four girls,
l'm coming home with four girls.
Hi. I'm looking
for a couple of college boys...
who might live here or have friends here.
I don't talk to anybody. People annoy me.
- What?
- She found him with the blonde again.
She's gonna knock on every door
in the entire building?
- Yep.
- Wow.
Hello! Is anyone home?
Hello!
Let's go follow your mother.
I wonder, if I was missing,
if my mom would come looking for me.
- Paris, you know she would.
- Yeah, or at least she'd send somebody.
- Music.
- Let's go.
That's one of the guys.
- Yeah?
- Hi. Could you move, please?
- What?
- Thanks.
Did you miss me?
- Lorelai.
- Ms. Gilmore.
- Put the cups down. Let's move.
- Is there a problem?
Yeah. See those two idiots over there?
They're 16, underage. I bet you're not.
I also bet those big fancy party cups
aren't holding lemonade.
You really want to end any conversation
with me now. So just step aside, Skippy.
Move your asses. Outside, now!
I won't even begin to tell you
how completely insane it is...
to take off with strangers or drink things
that you don't know what's in them...
or act like you have a clue when you don't.
But if you ever pull a stunt like this again,
it will not be around my kid!
- Do you understand me?
- Yes.
Good. Now let's go.
I can't wait to meet your parents.
We have some catching up to do.
I think we'll just talk all night long.
You know what?
I think this is the best night l've ever had.
I cannot believe I missed it.
- The concert was amazing.
- Forget about the concert.
I wanted to see Lorelai pull those idiots
out of that apartment.
It definitely was a Kodak moment.
- You didn't wake me up.
- I set the clock.
But the clock stops ringing
once I throw it against the wall...
giving me ample time to fall back to sleep.
You, however, never stop yapping
no matter how hard I throw you...
thus ensuring the whole wake-up process.
- I'm gonna get a soda. Want anything?
- Gum.
The night of my fourteenth birthday back...
so I could right the
green hot pant-roller disco outfit wrong.
- Coming right up.
- Bye.
So, talk to anybody today?
- You mean Madeline or Louise or Paris?
- Yes.
- No.
- Right.
But I bet school tomorrow
will be interesting.
Oh, yes. Stories of Rory's crazy,
Bangles-obsessed mother...
ripping open apartment doors,
scaring the pointy-haired boys.
Totally uncool, man.
I had to do it, Rory.
They could have gotten hurt.
I know.
I thought inviting those girls out
would make it easier for you at school.
I've always thought 'easy'
is completely overrated.
That's my twisted girl.
Plus Paris decided
to let me split the debate time with her.
Wow! Wait, why am I wowing?
Because splitting debate time with her
is like doing...
that spitting-in-your-palm
and-shaking-hands friendship oath thing.
But way less gross. Good, l'm glad then.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
Find anything good?
Yeah. I got some refrigerator magnets
shaped like sushi for a nickel.
- So basically I scored.
- Good.
- About what happened the other day...
- Forget it.
- I was a jerk. I didn't mean it.
- I know. Really.
Yeah, well, I am sorry.
- I wanted to give this back to you.
- No. You bought it.
- I know, but it's yours, and I didn't know.
- Didn't know?
About the former owner.
If I had, I wouldn't have flaunted it
in front of you.
It's no big deal.
I was having a bad day, that's it.
Now I got magnetic sushi.
AIl's right with the world.
Okay, good. So here.
It obviously means something to you.
But you have to let things go
eventually, right?
But sometimes you need
a little something to remind you.
You wouldn't want to forget everything,
would you?
No, there was some stuff
I definitely would not want to forget.
So here, so you don't forget.
Thanks. Can I pay you for it?
- In coffee, absolutely.
- All right.
- I'm not pining.
- I know.
- Just remembering.
- Got it.
- Remembering is not pining.
- Absolutely right.
- It's a memento, like restaurant matches.
- I can see the resemblance.
Okay. Good.
- Bye, Luke.
- Bye.
OpenSubtitles recommends using Nord VPN